Guide to the William Sherman Burgoyne papers circa 1890-1964
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
William Sherman Burgoyne papers
circa 1890-1964
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Coll 602
Burgoyne, William Sherman, 1901-1964.
6.5 cubic feet 17 document cases and 3 oversize folders
Papers and images relating to the life and career of Methodist minister William Sherman Burgoyne.
William Sherman Burgoyne was born on October 24, 1901 in Stevensville, Montana, to James Henry and Lola Helena Burgoyne. He was a descendant of the British general John Burgoyne, who had been defeated at the Battle of Saratoga during the American Revolution. William S. Burgoyne attended several institutions of higher education, including the Kimball School of Theology at Willamette University, and became a Methodist minister.
During his career as minister, which lasted until his retirement in 1957, Reverend Burgoyne preached in a number of Oregon towns including Hood River, McFarland, LaGrande, Turner, Cresswell, Sheridan, Lakewood, and Marshfield, as well as in Portland, Oregon, and Spokane, Washington. In 1934, he took a trip to the Holy Land, and for several years afterwards gave lectures at various Oregon churches about his experiences and observations from his travels.
In 1944, while Burgoyne was minister at the Asbury Methodist Church in Hood River, Oregon, the local chapter of the American Legion removed the names of 16 Japanese Americans from local memorial listing local citizens serving in the Armed Forces, claiming that they were dual citizens of Japan and the United States, and therefore suspect and unwelcome. Burgoyne publicly criticized the move, and he and his wife Doris gained national attention for their unyielding stance against bigotry and discrimination. Although his speaking out earned the enmity of locals and led to a decline in his church’s membership, in 1947 the Council Against Intolerance in America honored Burgoyne with the Thomas Jefferson Prize.
In addition to his preaching and social activism, Burgoyne joined the Grand Lodge of Oregon Freemasons in 1941, and was involved with the Masons for the rest of his life. He was elected Master of the Hood River Lodge in 1944.
Burgoyne married Doris Caple in 1920, with whom he had one daughter, Ruth. He died while on vacation in Yuma, Arizona, in 1964.
The collection consists of materials relating to the life and career of Methodist minister William Sherman Burgoyne. In addition to personal papers and photographs, the collection reflects Burgoyne’s social activism, particularly his opposition to discrimination towards Japanese Americans. Other significant portions of the collection pertain to Burgoyne’s membership in the Freemasons, and his travels in 1934 to North Africa, the Holy Land, and Europe, as well as the lectures he gave about said travels.
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series A: Personal and professional papers
Series B: Freemasonry
Series C: Activism
Series D: Travel to the Holy Land
Series E: Photographs and postcards
Series F: Other materials
Series G: Travel lantern slides
The collection is open to the public.
Lib. Acc. 29067
Wedding dress, 3 gavels, 3 masonic aprons, and cross-stitch sample were separated to Artifacts Collection, Oregon Historical Society.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Burgoyne, William Sherman, 1901-1964--Archives; Burgoyne, William Sherman, 1901-1964--Photographs; Burgoyne, Doris, 1901-1961; Burgoyne, Doris, 1901-1961--Photographs
Burgoyne family
Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Oregon; Council Against Intolerance in America; Japanese American Citizens League
Hood River (Or.)--Social action; Africa, North--Description and travel; Africa, North--Photographs; Egypt--Description and travel; Egypt--Photographs; Middle East--Description and travel; Middle East--Photographs; Palestine--Description and travel; Palestine--Photographs; Europe--Description and travel; Europe--Photographs; Italy--Description and travel; Italy--Photographs
Freemasonry--Oregon; Social action--Oregon; Methodism--Oregon; Japanese Americans--Oregon--Hood River.; Japanese Americans--Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945
Religion; Civil Rights; Civic Activism; Japanese Americans; Oregon
Correspondence.; Postcards; Clippings (information artifacts); Newsletters; Printed ephemera; Scrapbooks; Lantern slides; Photographs
- Personal and professional papers, 1922-1964; Series A
  - Bulletin re Methodist conference, circa 1937 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Certificate awarded to Burgoyne by McMinnville Rotary Club, 1935 August 9 (Box-folder 1/2)
    Burgoyne had been a guest speaker at the club.
  - Revolving fund certificate from Hood River Grange Supply Company, 1947 March 1 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Certificate of Retirement, 1957 June 14 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Certificate from War Finance Committee, 1943 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Columbia College yearbook, The Cayuse, 1923 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Columbia College yearbook, The Cayuse, 1924 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Commencement address, "Electives", undated (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Correspondence, Subseries 1
    - Correspondence re application to serve as chaplain in the armed forces, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Letter re ten dollar donation to Burgoyne's church, 1949 January 19 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Greeting cards, 1948, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Note from James Henry Burgoyne, 1940 September (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Letter from James Henry Burgoyne, 1940 October 19 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Letter from James Henry Burgoyne, 1940 December 25 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Letters from Lola Helena Burgoyne, 1953; undated (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Telegram from "Mother" to William Sherman Burgoyne, 1948 December 3 (Box-folder 1/16)
      Presumably sent by Lola Helena Burgoyne.
    - Letter from William Sherman Burgoyne to James Henry Burgoyne, 1947 April 21 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Letters from William Sherman Burgoyne to classmates at Kimball School of Theology, 1933 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Thank-you note from family of Josephine Caple, 1948 (Box-folder 1/19)
      Caple was Burgoyne's mother-in-law.
    - Letter from Marion S. Felter, 1942 March 9 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Letter from Portland Mayor Fred L. Peterson, 1955 May 25 (Box-folder 1/21)
      Letter thanks Burgoyne for delivering invocation at City Hall.
    - Letter from John Phillip Schmook, 1944 March 14 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Diploma and certificate awarded to Burgoyne by Methodist Episcopal Church, 1930 June 28-29 (Box-folder Oversize 1)
  - Educational diplomas, 1924; 1928; 1932; undated (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Guest book for William Sherman and Doris A. Burgoyne's 25th wedding anniversary celebration, 1945 March 16 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Itinierary for San Francisco trip, 1964 March (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Renewal of license to preach the Gospel, 1922 July (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Meier & Frank account balances, 1937 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - "The Methodist Youth Fellowship: A Brief Description of the Youth Program of the Methodist Church", 1941 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Newspaper column, "Meditations, 1935-1938; undated (Box-folder 1/29)
  - Handwritten notes for lectures/discussions, circa 1941 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Materials re Oregon Conference of the Methodist Church, 1961, 1963 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - Oregon Conference Methodist Youth Fellowship, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - Program fro Willamette University commencement ceremony, 1932 June 13 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Scrapbook (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Sermons, radio addresses, and ephemera, undated (Box-folder 3/2)
    Materials removed from a three-ring binder.
  - Funeral sermons, undated (Box-folder 3/3-3/5)
  - Sermon, "Lincoln: A Man of Poise in a World of Panic", 1941 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Service program, "Praise and Thanksgiving for Peace", 1945 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Service programs for Asbury Methodist Church, Hood River, Oregon, 1946 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Service program for Asbury Methodist Church, Hood River, Oregon, 1948 May 2 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Service program for Lents Methodist Church, Portland, Oregon, 1948 August 1 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Service program for Lents Methodist Church, Portland, Oregon, 1949 January 30 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Service program for Lents Methodist Church, Portland, Oregon, 1950 October 15 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Program for Rose City Park Methodist Church Easter service, 1959 March 29 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Service programs for Methodist Church of Sheridan, Oregon, 1935 October (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Service program for University Park Methodist Church, Portland, Oregon, 1954 August 29 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Service program for University Park Methodist Church, Portland, Oregon, 1955 May 1 (Box-folder 3/16)
- Freemasonry, 1928-1962; Series B
  - Address by Dr. Albert A. Witham, circa 1942 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Address given at 57th Annual Conclave, circa 1942 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Grand Master annual addresses, 1944; 1946; 1959 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Advertisements for Masonic Analyst/Oregon Mason, undated (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Articles and publications, Subseries 1
    - Catalog for Masonic costumes and supplies, 1943 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Catalog, the Temple Publishers, "Books for Freemasons", 1943 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Clippings and articles re Freemasonry (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Issue of The Greater Light, 1959 June (Box-folder 3/24)
    - History of the Grand Lodge of A. F. & A. M. of Oregon, from 1846 to 1901 Inclusive, Vol. 1, 1961 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - How Masonry Came to Oregon, 1948 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Masonic Analyst articles, 1942 March; 1943 March; 1950 March (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Issue of Masonic Analyst, 1942 October 6 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Issue of Masonic Tribune, 1958 August 25 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Oregon Freemason article, "Speculative Marks", 1953 August (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Issue of Oregon Mason, 1946 September (Box-folder 4/6)
    - "Mormonism and Masonry: A Look Today at an Old Utah Problem", 1954 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Proof copy of William S. Burgoyne's article, "The Antiquity of Masonry", 1942 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Scholarly articles on masonry, undated (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Issue of Star of Oregon, 1958 May (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Uniform Work Instructions, 1955 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Certificates, 1944-1960 (Box-folder 4/12, Oversize 2)
  - Chapter roster, 1944 December 31 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Clipping with photo of Masonic installation ceremony participants, including Doris Burgoyne, 1947 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Code book, undated (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Correspondence, Subseries 2
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1960; 1962 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Correspondence with Elbert Bede, 1944 March (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Letter from Stanley V. Cochran, 1941 October 31 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Letters to W. R. Lee from A & C Feldenheimer, Inc. re Masonic emblems, 1928 December 29; 1929 January 2 (Box-folder 5/9)
      Includes sketches of how emblems should appear. Documents probably came into Burgoyne's possession when he was Master of Hood River Lodge.
    - Handwritten memo from Burgoyne to "Brother Marshall" and Kent Shoemaker, circa 1944 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Directories, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Doric Lodge No. 132 Communications and Trestle Boards, 1957; 1960 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Election notice, 1942 November 19 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Membership election notices, 1944 January 6 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Event notices and invitations, 1941-1944; 1959 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Event programs, 1942-1963; undated (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Financial records, Subseries 3
    - Bill from Marshfield Lodge of Perfection, 1943 December 22 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Blanco Lodge No. 48 checks and receipts, 1941 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Statement and notice from Blanco Lodge No. 48, 1941 December (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Hood River Lodge budget, 1942 (Box-folder 6/4)
      Copy which was sent to Burgoyne circa 1944.
  - Blank form of notice for committee report due date, circa 1944 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Grand Lodge of Oregon Constitution and by-laws, 1951 June (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Holder for Knights Templar membership card, undated (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Hood River Commandery directory/calendar, 1941 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Hood River Lodge announcements, 1943 December (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Hood River Lodge directory/calendars, 1945, 1947, 1958 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Lents Lodge Trestle Board, 1960 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - List of constituent lodges in Grand Lodge of Oregon, 1959 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - List of degrees conferred at Hood River Lodge, 1944 January-March (Box-folder 6/12)
  - List of elected and appointed Masons at 94th Annual Communication of Grand Lodge of Oregon, 1944 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - List of Initiates, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - List of names, undated (Box-folder 6/15)
    Names are presumably of Freemasons.
  - List of names to be added to the 1941 Hood River Lodge Calendar, 1944 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - List of Oregon Lodges, undated (Box-folder 6/17)
  - List of Oregon Masons struck from the roll, reinstated, withdrawn, or suspended, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - M. E. M. Degree lecture, undated (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Masonic Code of Oregon and Manual of the Lodge, 1940 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - "Masonry Defined", circa 1943 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Multnomah Lodge No. 1 monthly bulletin, 1959 January (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Notes on 57th Annual Assembly, Grand Council, Royal and Select Masters, circa 1942 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Notes on 83rd Annual Convocation, circa 1942 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Notes from Grand Lodge School of Instruction, 1957 June 10-11 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Handwritten notes re Masonry, undated (Box-folder 6/26)
  - Typed and handwritten notes re Mansonry, undated (Box-folder 6/27)
  - Handwritten poem about Masonry on back of blank form, undated (Box-folder 6/28)
  - Philalethes Society materials, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 6/29)
  - "Pit Falls Along the Road", undated (Box-folder 6/30)
  - Poster with text about history of Freemasons in Oregon, 1941 (Box-folder Oversize 3)
  - Program for Super-Excellent Masters Degree Performance, 1946 April 9 (Box-folder 6/31)
  - Remarks by William Sherman Burgoyne upon being elected Master of Hood River Lodge, 1944 (Box-folder 6/32)
  - Report of Committee on Necrology, circa 1944 (Box-folder 6/33)
  - Ribbons, 1942, 1946 (Box-folder 6/34)
  - Sunrise Lodge No. 196 Trestle Boards, 1960 May-June, 1961 September (Box-folder 6/35)
  - "Third Lecture", undated (Box-folder 6/36)
- Activism, 1940-1955; Series C
  - An American Answer to Intolerance, 1940 (Box-folder 6/37)
  - Articles and clippings, Subseries 1
    - Compilation of Christian Century articles about Burgoyne, 1946 (Box-folder 6/38)
    - "The Great American Swindle," by Bradford Smith, 1947 (Box-folder 6/39)
    - "Our Worst Wartime Mistake," by Eugene V. Rostow, 1945 September (Box-folder 6/40)
    - Untitled article by Richard J. Walsh re immigration law, circa 1947 (Box-folder 6/41)
    - Clippings re anti-Japanese American discrimination and reactions thereto (Box-folder 6/42)
    - Clippings and ephemera re immigration and anti-discrimination legislation (Box-folder 6/43)
    - Clippings re Japanese Americans, circa 1947 (Box-folder 6/44)
    - Clippings re recognition for Burgoyne's activism, 1946-1947, undated (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Clippings re social concern and activism (Box-folder 7/2)
      Clippings do not mention Burgoyne.
  - Correspondence, Subseries 1
    - Letter from Fannie K. Friedman and enclosed Department of Justice press release re "Race Situation Directive", 1946 March 16 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Letter from Mike Masaoka of Japense American Citizens League, 1947 July 29 (Box-folder 7/4)
      Letter congratulates Burgoyne on his appointment to a church in Spokane, and provides contact information for local Japanese American Citizens League offices.
    - Letter from Carl Soule re article on Hood River controversy, 1945 December 3 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Facts about Japanese Americans, 1946 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Editorial, "For Valor!" by Richard L. Neuberger, 1946 December 3 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Handwritten piece describing Burgoyne's stance against bigotry, circa 1946 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Invitation card, "Protest Stereotype!", circa 1951 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Issue of Hood River News, 1945 January 26 (Box-folder 7/10)
    Includes article about American Legion headquarters asking Hood River chapter to reinstate names of Japanese-American soliders on the local monument.
  - Issue of "Mid-Columbia Bulletin" with article about Burgoyne, 1947 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Issue of Reader's Digest with article on Hood River Controversy, 1946 November (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Issue of The Saturday Reivew of Literature, 1946 August 10 (Box-folder 7/13-7/15)
    3 copies of the same issue, which includes a piece on the Hood River controversy. Each copy includes inserted clippings and ephemera
  - Issue of The Vagabond with piece about Hood River Controversy, 1946 December (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Issue of "Wallace J. Millers Newsletter," "Friends, We Are Ashamaed of Hood River", 1945 April (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Legislative bills, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Letter to editor by William S. Burgoyne re Silver Shirts, circa 1939 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Paid open letter in Hood River News by Avon W. Sutton, "Witch Burning", 1945 May 25 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Nisei in Uniform, circa 1944 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - "Pertinent Facts about Relocation Centers and Americans of Japanese Ancestry", 1944 November 23 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1955 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Thomas Jefferson Prize and speaking tour, Subseries 2
    - Address given by Burgoyne upon receiving prize, 1947 April 13 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Contract with Everett James Starr, 1947 April 17 (Box-folder 8/8)
      Contract gives Starr exclusive rights to any articles or books about activism that led to Burgoyne's receiving the Thomas Jefferson prize.
    - Correspondence, 1947 February-May (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Issue of Willamette Alumnus with piece about Burgoyne receiving prize, 1947 May (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Itinerary for trip to receive prize and subsequent speaking tour, 1947 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Notes and ephemera from trip to receive prize and subsequent speaking tour, 1947 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Program for Thomas Jefferson Prize presentation dinner, 1947 April 13 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Program for service led by Burgoyne at Japanese Methodist Church, New York City, 1947 April 13 (Box-folder 8/14)
    - Transcript of interview of Burgoyne by Nancy Osgood, 1947 April (Box-folder 8/15)
- Travel to the Holy Land, 1929-1952; 1934; Series D
  Additional ephemera from this trip is located in the scrpabook in folder 2/1.
  - An Atlas of the Life of Christ (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Brochure for 1935 Annual Pilgrimage Cruise (Box-folder 8/16)
    Burgoyne did not partake in the 1935 cruise.
  - Ephemera, Subseries 1
    Includes items that were perhaps not created in 1934, but which Burgoyne acquired in 1934.
    - Christmas cards with sprig of gradd and pressed flowers from the Holy Land (Box-folder 8/18)
    - Hotel stationery (Box-folder 8/19)
    - Hotel stickers/decals, calling cards, etc. (Box-folder 8/20)
    - James Boring Company stickers/decals (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen stationery (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen stickers/decals (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Issue of Cruise News, 1934 March 3 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Published letter from Bud Robinson, 1934 March (Box-folder 9/3)
    Letter mentions Burgoyne by name.
  - Memo book with notes, 1934 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Handwritten newsletter, "The Television", 1935 November 20 (Box-folder 9/5)
    Includes drawing and poem relating to Burgoyne's battles with seasickness during his trip. Removed from scrapbook in 2/1.
  - Typed and handwritten notes re travels, 1934 (Box-folder 9/6)
    Presumably used as the basis for Burgoyne's lectures. Covers North Africa and Europe. Removed from a 3-ring binder.
  - Typed and handwritten notes re travels, 1934 (Box-folder 9/7)
    Presumably used as the basis for Burgoyne's lectures. Covers the Holy Land. Removed from a three-ring binder.
  - Notice of deposit, 1934 January 22 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Passenger list for Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen ship Europa, 1934 March 30 (Box-folder 9/9)
    Ship by which Burgoyne returned to the United States. Folder contains two copies, one of which includes a handwritten note from a fellow passenger, addressed to Burgoyne's wife, complimenting Burgoyne's conduct and demeanor during the voyage.
  - Programs, clippings, and ephemera re lectures on travels, 1934-1936, 1952, undated (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Souvenir scrapbook re travel and lectures, 1934 November (Box-folder 9/11)
    Presented to Burgoyne by the First Methodist Church of Klamath Falls, Oregon.
  - "Traveller's Note-Book for Palestine", 1931 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Valentine's Day note, 1934 February 14 (Box-folder 9/13)
    Note written while Burgoyne was crossing the Atlantic on the ship Columbus.
- Photographs and postcards, circa 1890-1961; Series E
  - Album, circa 1900-1925 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Album, circa 1930 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Personal and family photographs, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 12/2-12/7)
  - William S. Burgoyne and family on Mt. Hood, 1930, 1931, undated (Box-folder 12/8)
  - William S. Burgoyne and family at firewatch tower, unidentified location, 1955 August (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Colorized photograph of Burgoyne preaching, circa 1945 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Colorized photographs of William S. and Doris Burgoyne, circa 1945 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Family photographs, circa 1890-1918 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Gifford photo set of Mt. Hood, undated (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Group photo at Methodist Conference in Milton, Oregon, 1928 Agust 22 (Box-folder Box 15)
    Access to this item is restricted for preservation reasons.
  - Group photo at Northwest Assembly Conference in Corvallis, Oregon, 1926 August 25 (Box-folder Box 15)
  - Hood River Japanese American families, circa 1945-1961 (Box-folder 12/14)
  - Masonic photographs, 1944-circa 1960 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Postcard of Methodist Church in Stevensville, Montana, circa 1925 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Montana postcard, undated (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Postcards of Okinawa, circa 1946 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Postcards from trip to receive Thomas Jefferson Prize and subsequent speaking tour, 1947 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Spokane, Washington, 1948 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Photographs from trip to New York for Thomas Jefferson Prize and subsequent speaking tour, 1947 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Travel photographs, 1934 (Box-folder 14/1-14/3)
    Large prints of selected photographs taken during Burgoyne's trip to the Holy Land, North Africa, and Europe.
  - Travel snapshots, 1934 (Box-folder 13/8-13/9)
  - Postcards and souvenir photographs from Holy Land travels., Subseries 1
    Creation dates unknown, but images were purchased by Burgoyne during his travels to the Holy Land and elsewhere in 1934.
    - Postcards of Cairo and environs (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Postcards of Greece (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Colorized postcards of the Holy Land (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Postcards of the Holy Land (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Postcards of Istanbul (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Postcards of Nazareth (Box-folder 13/15)
    - Norddeutscher Lloyd postcards (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Postcards of North Africa (Box-folder 13/17)
    - Postcards of Pompeii, Italy (Box-folder 13/18)
    - Set of postcards of Rome (Box-folder 13/19)